Alexis Brownstein, MBA, CPIM

208 Pebble Creek Court, Pennington, NJ 08534 Phone: (856) 912-1376 Email: alexis@drdatabase.com

Professional Profile

Versatile, results-driven business analyst and software developer experienced in all areas of the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC). Successfully collaborates with users to create effective systems to meet business needs. Creative problem solver who welcomes challenges and is committed to excellence. Motivated, organized self-starter with exceptional communication skills. Comfortable working with all levels of an organization.

Key Qualifications Summary / Core Competencies

- Business Analysis
- Requirements Gathering/Analysis
- Data Migration
- Database Design
- Programming
- System Testing
- Software Deployment
- Project Management
- User and Technical Documentation
- User Training
- User Support/Helpdesk

- Databases MS-Access, SQL Server, MySQL
- Programming Languages SQL, VBA, ASP, VBScript, PHP
- Scripting Languages HTML, JavaScript
- Software/Tools -eQMS/EHS/ERP/CRM/MRP Software, MS-Access, MS-PowerPoint, MS-Excel, MS-Outlook, MS-Project, MS-Visio, Helpdesk Software, Screenshot Software, SQL Server Mgmt Studio, VS Code, Zoom, Teams, Slack, Git/GitHub
- Foreign Language Skills French (Fluent Speaking & Writing), Spanish (Advanced Speaking & Writing)
- Education/Certifications *MBA*, *BA*, *CPIM* (Certified in Production & Inventory Management)

Career Summary

Tatum by Randstad

Business Analyst (Consultant)

8/2022 - present

Report to CFO in Finance Department at a biotech company. Create and automate financial data reports using VBA in MS-Excel and MS-Access.

Universal Display Corporation - Ewing, NJ

Business Analyst/Software Developer/Consultant

2/2007 - 4/2022

Universal Display Corporation develops state-of-the-art, organic light emitting diode (OLED) technologies. Its chemical products are used in cell phone displays, television screens and other lighting products.

Key Responsibilities and Accomplishments:

- Partnered with internal stakeholders, technical team members and vendor consultants to review user stories and create requirements documentation, deliverables and progress tracking
- Prioritized and planned activities based on deadlines, resources and other factors
- Operated independently, as needed, to take on additional responsibilities to keep projects on-time and on-budget
- Successfully managed eQMS/EHS cloud system implementation (ETQ Reliance) while dealing with changing deadlines and scope, and an unexpected immediate work-from-home requirement due to the pandemic
- Facilitated regular meetings to review project status and adjust project plans as needed
- Released incremental software enhancements and bug fixes on a regular basis
- Collaborated with users to develop accurate test case documentation and assign testing to get stakeholder approval in UAT before deployment to Production systems
- Authored easy-to-understand technical, user and training documentation, including release notes
- Planned and led user training sessions on software implementations and changes
- Rectified user issues in person and virtually (Zoom/Teams), and documented in helpdesk systems
- Analyzed and developed data and user group permissions (Active Directory/SQL Server)
- Successfully created and supported the first versions of UDC's Quality, R&D and Sales production systems
- Competently established UDC's data warehouse
- Independently developed smart tools to provide users with efficient and secure data access, as well as reports in Excel and other formats

Alexis Brownstein resume (continued)

Universal Display Corporation – Key Responsibilities and Accomplishments (continued)

- Cleverly constructed tools/reports, and customized logic for purchased software, such as ETQ Reliance, saving hundreds of thousands of dollars in outside consulting fees and accelerating the release timelines
- Expertly managed, maintained and supported 12+ live systems concurrently with no major downtime
- Successfully developed and managed upgrade to Office 365 of major data tool shared by 40+ users
- Capably worked with users in all functional areas to develop complex but user-friendly systems to manage company data, saving users countless hours in the performance of their duties

Career Summary Continued

Dr. Database, LLC - Mount Laurel, NJ

07/2004 - 06/2011

Owner / Consultant

- Diligently managed the business while personally handling over 25 clients of all sizes
- Successfully created large MS-Access multi-user databases used by clients to run their businesses
- Generated company website projects with easy-to-use interfaces for clients to manage their data with a content management tool
- Created programs to load old data into the new systems
- Hired consultants to help with large projects and managed their work
- Competently resolved technical support issues
- Collaborated with clients to create useful, efficient custom systems to meet their needs

Subaru of America - Cherry Hill, NJ

11/2001 - 10/2004

HRIS Analyst

- Utilized VBA to create Access databases to track many HR processes
- Successfully created systems for other functional areas of the company, such as customer sales
- Created numerous complex reports to improve Management access to data for decision-making
- Competently developed data conversion programs in VBA and SQL to transfer old data to new systems
- Creatively enhanced existing systems to improve the user experience and reduce time spent on job duties

Education and Training

MBA Rutgers University, Camden, NJ (Honors)

BA Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ – Major: French (High Honors)

Certifications APICS (American Production and Inventory Control Society) - CPIM (Certified in

Production & Inventory Management)